♪ ♪
Do you want subtitles for any video?
-=[ ai.OpenSubtitles.com ]=-
Previously on Star Trek:
Strange New Worlds...
BATEL [over comms]: To any Federation
vessels in range. need help.
Under attack by the Gorn.
APRIL: The Federation's at
a dangerous point
in our relationship
with the Gorn Hegemony.
UHURA: It looks like
a demarcation line.
UNA: With Parnassus Beta
and all their forces
on the far side of the line.
PIKE: Unfortunately.
that is where
I believe our people
are being held.
I don't plan on
leaving them behind.
[growling]
If somewhere in my
head is the answer
to saving the Enterprise. then
that's a risk I have to take.
Take this. It'll help you hide.
[echoing]: Run!
Montgomery Scott
at your service.
ORTEGAS: How are you not dead?
Well. I figured out how
to hide in plain sight.
You built a Gorn transponder?
Eh. basically. to a scanner.
the shuttle looked
like a Gorn ship.
Could you build another
device like the one you made?
-What's happening?
-Captain Batel is in need
-of immediate sedation.
-Happened yesterday.
I'm not giving up on her.
I have no intention
of doing that.
Captain. the transporter's
not currently picking up
anyone on the surface.
[shouting]
Admiral April's ordering
our immediate withdrawal.
SPOCK: The colonists
and the landing party
appear to have been beamed up
-by the Gorn.
-Orders. Captain?
ANNOUNCER: And now.
the conclusion.
UNA: Orders. Captain?
MITCHELL: Shields at 50%.
-UNA: Captain.
-MITCHELL: Captain.
[alarm blaring]
UNA: Orders. Captain?
Uhura. repeat
April's last order.
UHURA: Retreat and rendez...
Retreat and rendezvous
with the fleet. sir.
-He gave coordinates.
-But he didn't say immediately?
-All right. who's got ideas?
-Diversionary tactics.
We're too boxed in.
Vent the nacelles.
create a cloud?
-We need to be able to see.
-Jam their comms
so they can't
coordinate attacks.
That's it. That's the one.
The Gorn use light for
ship-to-ship messaging.
UHURA: I'm modulating
the deflector array
to emit a spectrum. Should
confuse them for a bit.
All right. now how do we beam
our people back to Enterprise?
Scans indicate the Gorn ships
are transport-resistant.
So. even if we get
past the shields.
-we need authorization codes.
-No time to hack codes.
Retreat and rescue.
It's the best of a
bunch of bad options.
So how do we track
this specific ship
across light-years of space?
SPOCK: Wolkite. A rare element
that contains
subspace gauge bosons.
If we modified a
homing beacon...
The Gorn would see a beacon
coming from a mile away.
Not if it's a torpedo.
We tag 'em with a dud.
The Gorn won't know
what we're up to.
MITCHELL: Shields at 30%.
For this to succeed. we
still need to penetrate
the Gorn's defensive systems.
MITCHELL: We've
been hitting them
with everything we've
got. it doesn't do much.
Uh. energy shields
work on harmonics.
If we find the
right frequency...
We can ram the ship.
SPOCK: Indeed.
When our shields make
contact with theirs.
they will create a destructive
interference pattern
and momentarily interrupt
both frequencies.
MITCHELL: With our shields
down. we'd be sitting ducks.
-We'd only have one shot.
-That's all we need. Mitchell. bring us around.
head-to-head with the destroyer.
Time to play a game of chicken.
UHURA: All decks.
prepare for impact.
Full impulse on your
orders. Captain.
Inertial dampeners to maximum.
Everybody hold onto something.
Una... let's hit it.
PIKE: Fire torpedoes.
-Helm. warp us out of here.
-On it.
Hang in there. guys.
PIKE: Space.
The final frontier.
These are the voyages of
the starship Enterprise.
Its five-year mission:
to explore strange new worlds...
...to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
...to boldly go where
no one has gone before.
♪ ♪
♪
Captain. we've arrived
at the rendezvous point.
The USS Pablo Picasso
is hailing to greet us.
It's Admiral April. sir.
He's beaming aboard
now to debrief.
-[sighs] More needles?
-Yes. just a few more pokes.
I mean. without these.
your body will go necrotic
in the stasis field. so...
-Things turn purple. It's not pretty.
-Mm.
I've never been
frozen solid before.
It's not an exciting prospect.
Well. as soon as we work out
this little Gorn infection.
you'll be up and around again.
So this could be like a Rip
Van Winkle thing for me.
I see you more as
a Sleeping Beauty.
Listen. I meant
what I said before.
The moment it looks
like me or the crew.
you take me out.
Don't think about that.
Stasis will prevent
you and the Gorn
from any type of
cellular growth.
There's another
side to the coin.
Whatever it takes.
Whatever it takes. I promise.
-I'm. uh. I'm gonna give you a sedative now.
-[device clicks]
And when you wake up.
you will be Gorn-free.
-[grunting]
-[alarms sounding]
Epinephrine and
neutralizer. stat!
Her body's rejecting the serum.
Sickbay to bridge.
Uh. I have an update.
and it's not good.
Bottom line it for me.
Captain Batel is
allergic to cryoserum.
We can't put her in stasis.
So she's back on
a ticking clock?
The Gorn will hatch
from her body in. um...
[sniffles] in less than a day.
I'm stuck trying to
find a treatment.
Um... uh...
maybe if Joseph was
here. I could...
I'm sending help. Christine...
...I believe in you. Help her.
I'll do my best. Captain.
SPOCK: Captain. I
may not be a doctor.
but I will dedicate all of
my abilities to Captain Batel
until her Gorn infection
is... resolved.
PIKE: Just stand by?
You have the entire fleet
out there ready to go.
APRIL: It's a show of force.
First we need to
establish patrols.
Do they really think the
Gorn are just gonna stop
and go home after they raided
those colonies? [scoffs]
Look. it's a tough situation.
but we have to manage it
one piece at a time.
-There are innocent lives at stake. Bob.
-And I get that.
But it's happening outside
of our jurisdiction.
Oh. come on. Bob.
Apart from your
reckless dogfight.
these attacks do not
involve the Federation.
We have regulations. Chris.
So. because it's non-Federation
citizens that are dying.
we do nothing?
We have an obligation
to our member worlds.
Billions of lives.
To rush into a fight right
now puts all of them at risk.
We can't do it.
We're still recovering
from the Klingon War.
You are absolutely right. and
the Gorn sense our weakness.
We are prey.
They will push
this Hegemony line
further and further
into Federation space.
And you know they will.
And by the time we
actually get around
to doing something about it...
it'll be way too late.
I heard about the landing party.
Yeah. and a couple
hundred colonists. too.
And Marie?
She's in sickbay.
Officially. your orders are to
monitor the demarcation line
for any encroachment
by the Gorn.
Okay. And unofficially?
How do we punch back and
show them we aren't prey?
Yeah. I can do that.
PELIA: This
contraption of yours.
what's it supposed to do again?
Emit a polarized EM signature
that tricks the Gorn
into thinking we're one of them.
It's like a cloaking device.
And how. exactly.
does it do that?
Ah. if I'm being honest.
I don't really remember.
I was kind of in the moment.
Well. now I'm going to
ask a silly question.
to which I'm pretty
sure I know the answer.
[sighs] Not this again.
It's like being back
in lecture hall.
How would you know that?
You were never there.
I was there. in the back.
Did you record a
work-in-progress log
while you were
jury-rigging this up?
What. you mean as the Gorn
were tearing our ship apart?
First rule in engineering.
Scotty: write it down.
There's a reason
we track our work
no matter what the
circumstance. and this.
this right now. this is
precisely the reason.
Pardon the interruption.
How long before you
get that working?
Oh. Captain Pike. the thing is.
it worked on my wee shuttle.
-but the Enterprise is...
-How soon do you need it. Captain?
We're headed into Gorn
space. so now would be good.
It'll be up and working before
we cross the Hegemony line.
I'm counting on it. as are the
lives of everyone on board.
We're going after
our missing crew.
with or without that device.
Understand?
Well. that's no pressure.
♪ ♪
-YOUNG LA'AN: Mom?
-LA'AN'S MOTHER: La'An. be brave.
LA'AN: Not believing you're gonna
die is what gets you killed.
It's the Gorn.
Wake up.
-Wake up!
-[screams]
[grunting]
[grunts]
[yells]
[panting]
You can do this.
Always start with the doctor.
[M'Benga grunting]
[retches]
-[coughs]
-Okay.
[groaning]
Holy crap. my hand!
-Half my hand is frickin' gone.
-LA'AN: Look at me.
Erica. look at me.
Look at me. Relax.
It's going to be okay.
[Ortegas groaning]
M'BENGA: We can fix this
when we get back to the ship.
ORTEGAS: Please. Okay.
-M'BENGA: Try to stay calm.
-ORTEGAS: Okay.
ORTEGAS: How?
How do we get back to the ship?
What about them?
If we free them one at a time.
we'll only get a handful out.
SAM: If that. Look
how long it took
for the four of us to get loose.
This is a massive
digestive chamber.
And it's working
its way through...
looks like a-a processing
plant for fuel.
Or just food for the Gorn.
I don't like the idea
of being anyone's lunch.
And even if we can wake them up.
one or a hundred.
we still don't have
a way out of...
wherever this is.
M'BENGA: One step at a time.
Sitting here doing nothing
is a death sentence.
SAM: And for all we know.
the Gorn were alerted
the moment that we woke up.
ORTEGAS: So the killer lizards
could already be on their way.
-They're coming.
-Don't be afraid.
La'An.
No matter what.
What's on your mind. Lieutenant?
You're right.
It's not just about us.
All of these people
will be dead soon.
SAM: Hey. This looks like
an evacuation pile.
Maybe whatever the ship
can't process. it expels.
[chuckles]
[squishing]
[grunting]
-[exhales]
-ORTEGAS: Ah.
Weapons from a crap pile.
Strangely. it's a step
in the right direction.
I don't want to save a
handful of colonists.
I want to save them all.
Everyone that's still
alive gets home.
Even if we have to
shoot our way out.
♪ ♪
[power sputters]
Ack. bawheid.
-That's not it.
-PELIA: The Gorn!
The Gorn! They're here!
Oh. shite.
PELIA: We're doomed. Scotty.
-No. no. no. no...
-We're all gonna die!
SCOTTY: It's working.
It's working. Tell the bridge
to patch it to the shields.
What? Is it too late?
PIKE: Bridge to science lab.
What's the status down there?
-We're about to enter Gorn space.
-Oh. you minx.
PELIA: It's up and
running. Captain.
We can patch it into
the shields now.
-Excellent. Pike out.
-That wasn't funny.
-It was fun.
-You nearly gave me a heart attack.
I did it 'cause I know you.
-No. you don't.
-Yes. with too much time on your hands. you fall apart.
but put a phaser to
your head and voilà.
Why do you care what I do?
You put up walls. Scotty.
You're too afraid
to take a risk.
I fixed what you wanted me to.
And you're
insubordinate to boot.
Well. technically
you're not my C.O.
She went down on the Stardiver.
May I be excused. sir?
[softly]: Oh. Scotty.
[door whooshes open]
MITCHELL: Approaching the Hegemony
demarcation line now. sir.
PIKE: Drop us out of warp.
-Start Mr. Scott's transponder.
-UNA: Transponder?
Pelia says it's more like a
modified EM pulse emitter.
Okay. then that makes sense.
The Gorn must not
use optical data.
They've evolved. so they
must rely on biometrics.
heat and EM signatures.
Well. time to see if
it actually works.
It should. I mean.
unless maybe one of them
decides to look out a window.
[device beeping]
MITCHELL: Captain. Gorn
hunters approaching.
Keep us steady and on course.
So far. I don't see any windows.
MITCHELL: It worked.
Uhura. do we still have a
signal from the wolkite beacon?
Aye. sir.
It's faint and getting
weaker but still there.
Any intel on where
they're headed?
UNA: An uncharted
binary star system.
The stellar activity there
is like nothing we've
ever seen before.
-Helm. plot a course.
-Captain. the radiation in that system is off the charts.
At a certain point. we can
only use impulse engines.
and our shields won't
be able to protect us.
Understood. We'll make it quick.
Mitchell. warp factor seven.
Aye aye. sir.
SPOCK: Intriguing.
The incubation has severely
altered her biochemistry.
CHAPEL: Her body
is now as dependent
on the Gorn hatchlings
as they are on her.
SPOCK: The perfect
host. inseparable.
Have you tried
microscopic debulking?
COMPUTER: Results completed.
CHAPEL: It's the last
simulation I ran.
COMPUTER: Probability
of fatality is 100%.
That's the chorus of the day.
It's every simulation I've run.
Computer. run scenarios
for microscopic debulking
factoring for an infusion
of Zadora extract.
-COMPUTER: Processing.
-CHAPEL: An Orion street drug?
Actually. that's
kind of brilliant.
You are the one who taught me
to look outside of the box.
[chuckles] It's "think."
but close enough.
Christine.
-I know you want to talk.
-I will be brief.
I simply want to apologize
for the way things
ended before you left.
I reacted poorly.
Apology accepted.
We're good.
The thought of losing you.
it affected me deeply.
I understand.
This has gotten complicated.
and I am not good
at complicated.
And I am still going
away for three months
to study with Roger Korby.
When I get back. let's
just see where we are then.
So you are saying that perhaps
some time apart
might be good for us?
[softly]: Spock.
Yeah.
But not like...
not like "us" us.
Like...
us as people.
Please don't do something
you think is romantic.
like wait for me or something.
COMPUTER: Zadora extract
scenario completed.
Probability of fatality is 100%.
SPOCK: No matter how
we approach this.
Batel's human DNA is...
Inadequate.
Her body goes into shock.
blood pressure drops.
And she dies.
Huh. Human physiology.
What if we gave her
some help there?
You have an idea.
-Illyrian.
-Illyrian DNA.
Una's blood.
it's designed to combat
infections in real time.
A plasma injection
could provide a boost
-to Batel's immunity.
-And we could attempt
the surgery without
her going into shock.
SPOCK: It is
against regulation.
but it could save her life.
Computer. run
scenario for surgery
factoring for a
plasma transfusion
from an Illyrian blood donor.
COMPUTER: Processing.
How did you put it once?
Some rules are
intended to be broken?
[laughs softly]
Almost exactly it.
LA'AN: There's the hangar.
Okay.
Everyone's clear on the plan?
SAM: Access the
ship's mainframe.
upload the Gorn
transporter codes...
Get them to the Enterprise.
To do that. we have to steal
a ship and fly it out of here.
M'BENGA: That one
doesn't look guarded.
Totally got this. not
impossible at all.
And it's true you can
fly anything. right?
Don't be rude. Of course I can.
LA'AN: Okay.
Let's get to that ship.
This is a good plan.
It's gonna work.
It's good. It's-it's...
It's a good plan. right?
It's a good plan.
Yeah. Yeah. Now all
we have to do is
not get caught by the Gorn.
[distant growling]
-Sam.
-Why would you say that?
What? Oh. come on.
you can't blame me.
LA'AN: Phasers to kill.
Time to go.
Uhura and I have
been poring over
all available data on the Gorn.
Confirmed attacks.
unverified sightings.
If it might be a Gorn.
we've checked it out.
And there's a lot more
out there than we thought.
UNA: You have to
squint a little.
But every Gorn
sighting correlates
to a pattern of
specific stellar events.
Coronal mass ejections. I
know this already. CMEs.
Stellar flares can
set off a frenzy.
Yes. the attacks
follow a pattern.
but so does Gorn inactivity.
Uhura is the one who found it.
There are long periods of time
where no Gorn
activity is reported.
Not so much as a rumor.
UNA: And in those instances.
there's unique stellar activity
that seems to trigger...
-Hibernation.
-UHURA: Yes.
We believe that the Gorn have
a long hibernation cycle.
Under the right conditions.
they become docile.
We can use that.
The science team
chipped in on the math
and was able to isolate the
presence of X-class flares
and supra-arcade down flows
that precede their absence.
Good work. both of you.
UNA: There's something else.
The data also suggests
that we could be
at the beginning of a long
cycle of Gorn aggression.
These attacks could
signal what could soon be
a full-scale Gorn invasion.
[comms chime]
MITCHELL: Dropping out of
warp in two minutes. sir.
Thank you. Mitchell. On our way.
[door whooshes open]
UNA: Spock and Chapel
know what they're doing.
I trust them
with a couple
liters of my blood.
Thank you for that.
They say it may
be her only hope.
For Marie. they can
take all they want.
This mission's already
off-the-record.
so nothing to report.
Chris.
take some of your own advice.
Focus on hope.
COMPUTER: Illyrian blood
donor scenario completed.
Probability of fatality: 86%.
That's the first one that's
given her any chance at all.
Albeit not a very high one.
I mean. we can't do the
surgery with these odds.
We're on to something.
Let's keep at it.
Indeed.
UNA: We're near
the radiation zone.
From here on. it's
impulse engines only.
[sighs]
Mitchell. you've
been running nonstop.
Call for relief.
With respect. I'm not
leaving the station
until we get everyone back.
Copy.
Thank you.
I have the wolkite signature.
We're coming up on
the enemy destroyer.
-How soon can we overtake them?
-Chris. we may be too late.
They've already entered
the radiation zone.
If we go any deeper
into this star system.
we put the entire crew at risk.
Helm. full stop.
Put the long-range visual
up on the main screen.
Is it me. or does it look like
that ship is going to
fly right into that star?
I see it. I don't believe it.
Telemetry confirms. Captain.
-We have to do something.
-Look.
MITCHELL: Did they
just lose power?
No.
I think it was intentional.
But why?
All auxiliary power
to the shields.
Give me as much time as possible
inside that radiation zone.
We're going after 'em.
MITCHELL: We've got
another CME flare coming.
-[grunting]
-[alarms sounding]
-She's coding.
-The Gorn hatchlings are activating.
Something has
accelerated their growth.
A 14% chance of survival is
better than certain death.
Let's prep her for surgery.
UHURA: I'm still getting a
ping on the wolkite signal.
UNA: We need to get to our
people while we still can.
The magnetic fields here
make navigation impossible.
UNA: That explains why the
Gorn go into a free fall.
They let the intense gravity
wells do most of the work.
No response from Starfleet.
UNA: It's all the radiation.
MITCHELL: And no
visuals on the ship
or what's beyond
the binary stars.
UNA: The light bends in a way
that creates a natural hologram.
They're essentially invisible
once they pass through it.
Makes for a great
defense system.
MITCHELL: Maybe it's
a landing sequence.
Could this be the
Gorn homeworld?
If it is. that's how
they go back to it.
[alarm chirps]
MITCHELL: Captain.
-something's moving out there.
-On screen.
Number One.
UNA: I've plotted
their trajectory.
Those ships are headed straight
for Federation territory.
-Warn Starfleet.
-It's a deep space relay.
I won't be able to confirm
if they receive it.
We need to go.
Get clear of this
system's interference.
Captain. if we lose our
lock on the wolkite signal.
I'm not sure we can
reestablish contact.
We'll lose the landing
party and the colonists.
We can drop a long-range
communication buoy.
Tie a signal to it.
That way we can
come back for them.
It's the best I've got.
Do it.
We have to stop this invasion.
Communication buoy is deployed.
Mitchell. stay on
that enemy fleet.
-Bringing her about.
-As soon as we can.
you warp out of here.
Full throttle until we
can alert Starfleet.
We're the only hope the
Federation's got right now.
Computer. engage
quarantine mode.
COMPUTER: Quarantine
mode engaged.
If this goes sideways. it's.
it's Valeo Beta all over again.
The probability of a
full-scale Gorn outbreak...
I really don't want to know.
Nurse Chapel. USS Enterprise...
...injecting Patient Batel
with experimental
plasma solution.
-Anything. Ensign?
-UHURA: Still jammed. sir.
The Gorn are transmitting
an interference signal.
How long before we clear these
binary stars and go to warp?
Not soon enough.
Those Gorn ships are moving
a lot faster than we are.
By the time we get a signal out.
the Gorn will be right on top
of the outer Federation worlds.
They're sitting ducks.
Mitchell. are we in shooting
distance of the Gorn?
[scoffs]: Chris.
Enterprise against
an entire armada?
We wouldn't stand a chance.
[sighs]
-Pike to science lab.
-[comms chime]
Pelia. I need you on the bridge.
PELIA [over comms]: Aye.
Captain. right away.
What are you up to?
You and Uhura.
you said stellar
flares can dictate
a Gorn's hunting
and resting cycles.
UHURA: Right.
We even know precisely what
kind of radiation signature
would tell the Gorn
to go to sleep.
-Um. sir. that's just a theory.
-[door whooshes open]
PIKE: So...
...we just need to
create a stellar flare.
SCOTTY: Oh. forgive
me for interrupting.
but you cannot make a
star do much of anything.
Certainly not
precisely. Captain.
Which is why we need
to become a CME. uh.
X-flare ourselves.
[chuckles] Eh...
Captain. look. Uh.
sorry. do you mind?
Eh. sure. using the ship
would allow us to modulate
the exact radiation
and EM signals we'd emit.
But you're basically
talking about
turning the ship into
an artificial star.
That's-that's nearly impossible.
-But not impossible.
-[stammers]
To do that. we'd
have to go deeper
into this deadly radiation zone.
fly right between those binary
stars out there. and create
some kind of competing
magnetic field
to draw particles away
from both of them.
Modify the deflector shields.
comms array. and. well...
[sighs] every-everything
else. really.
SCOTTY: Magnetize the hull
to attract stellar material.
It's one in a thousand
we'd get it done right
or don't blow ourselves up
along the way. and. look.
Yeah. I don't know.
I like those odds.
We'll just...
...turn it off
before we blow up.
Get it done.
CHAPEL: Patient is responding
favorably to the transfusion.
Ready to make the
first incision.
♪ ♪
Wait.
You know the most likely outcome
is the death of Captain Batel?
We just have to
have a little faith.
Perhaps we are looking at this
from the wrong perspective.
Instead of operating on Batel.
what if we treated the
Gorn inside of her?
We know they emerge to
feed. What if we feed them?
Satiate them to keep
them from coming out.
And when they are no
longer in defensive mode.
-dissolve them.
-And use Una's Illyrian plasma
to fight the multitude of
infections that will result
-from their reabsorption.
-Yes.
But we don't have enough time
to run another simulation.
As you suggested. perhaps
we just need a little faith.
ORTEGAS: Did we lose them?
M'BENGA: Maybe. but if so.
then not for long.
LA'AN: This is an interface.
They had them on the Gorn...
the Gorn breeding planet.
My brother Manu. he...
MANU: Don't be afraid.
Keep moving. no matter what.
M'BENGA: Hey.
Hey.
Are you okay?
You're here now. not back there.
Yeah. but here's not
great either. is it?
No. I suppose not.
LA'AN: I remember.
Let me try something.
This is amazing.
I'd love to take this apart.
figure out how it works.
Yeah. good idea. Let's
make a whole day of it.
Get snacks. hang out.
M'BENGA: Those look
like buffer signatures.
They are. And the
transport codes.
If we can get this
to the Enterprise.
then we can save the colonists.
All of them.
-[screeching]
-Guys...
♪
Get to the ship!
[screeches. growls]
[screeching]
[yelling]
[grunts]
[grunts. gasps]
-[growls]
-[Ortegas wheezes]
-[weapon whirring]
-[grunts]
MITCHELL: We are in position.
approaching the binary stars.
UNA: The moment we shut
down the EM emitter.
every single Gorn ship
is going to come at us.
Like moths to a flame.
Which is exactly what we want.
Everybody ready?
Make us shine like the sun.
♪ ♪
-[panting]
-[Gorn screeching]
[Ortegas grunts]
-[loud bang]
-ORTEGAS: The pilot seat.
Put me in the pilot seat.
Put me in the pilot seat!
Forget about it!
I can fly it. It has to be me.
She's right. We need to go.
[pained groans]
[groans with effort]
[sighs]
[chuckles weakly]
[grunting softly]
[grunting]
[Ortegas grunting]
Ah!
[screeches]
[grunts]
[gasping]
[snarls]
[alarm blaring]
We're covered in beta
particles and gamma rays.
This ship is hitting
critical levels of radiation!
-What are the Gorn doing?
-MITCHELL: They have broken ranks.
currently on intercept
course with Enterprise.
All right. so far. so good.
Now let's see if
they shoot at us.
Captain. I have a
signal bouncing off
the communications beacon.
It's La'An. sir.
-Enterprise. are you there?
-PIKE: La'An. where are you?
On our way. If
you can read me.
I'm sending you transport codes.
[breaking up]: Beam
the Parnassians out.
PIKE: We're trying
to beam you out.
but we're having
trouble getting a lock.
Do you copy?
They're gaining on us!
Enterprise. do you read me?
Beam the Parnassians out.
-[explosion]
-[pained grunt]
[screeches]
Captain. hull integrity is
approaching critical failure!
♪
Turn it off. Turn it off!
[alarm blaring]
Did it work?
Aye. sir. the last of
the Gorn have gone home.
What about the Parnassians?
Did we get them out in time?
UHURA: Yes. Captain.
The transport codes
from La'An worked.
Several hundred
colonists accounted for
and headed for the
overflow infirmary.
LA'AN [breaking up]: Captain.
we need immediate as...
Beam us out and have a
medical team standing by.
Pike to Engineering?
SCOTTY [over comms]: Aye. Captain.
we're using the transport codes
to hack into the Gorn hunter.
should be just a moment.
UNA: Chris. Chris. we did it.
We triggered a long
hibernation in the Gorn.
PIKE: Yeah...
But I can't help wondering
if we didn't just create
a problem for someone
else to solve later.
[comms beeping]
Captain. I'm getting a secure
channel from Admiral April.
Put him through.
APRIL: Chris. We just got
your priority message.
How much time do we have
before the Gorn ships get here?
Ignore last transmission.
We won't be seeing the Gorn.
at least not for a while.
APRIL: How certain are you?
Let's just say I found
a way to punch back.
[panting]
♪ ♪
Stay with me. Stay with me.
[labored breathing]
[weakly]: I did good.
Didn't I?
Stop. You're going to make it.
They'll have to try
harder than that.
I'm Erica Ortegas.
I fly the ship.
M'BENGA: Hold on. I got you.
[electricity crackles]
[door whooshes shut]
We did all we could.
It's in Captain
Batel's hands now.
Indeed.
Thank you.
I couldn't have done
that without you.
You're welcome.
How is she?
She's in the lab.
still in recovery.
[door whooshes open]
[door whooshes shut]
UNA [over comms]: Landing
Party accounted for
and getting treatment in
the overflow infirmary.
Erica is critical...
but stable.
Thanks for the update.
Once we clear the
radiation bands.
chart a course for
Earth. Warp us home.
UNA: Of course.
Number One out.
[door whooshes shut]
Okay.
Okay. Dad.
You win.
[sighs]
Our Father.
who art in heaven...
Chris?
You're awake.
Yeah. Which I assume means
that tiny Gorn didn't
pop out of my body
and kill everybody.
No.
No. no. no. We're still here.
Spock and Chapel came up
with a treatment. uh...
I'll have them walk you
through it later. but...
...you're still not
out of the woods yet.
How?
Una helped.
Chris. you shouldn't
have done that.
Marie. I've already lost
too much. all right?
So we can sit here
and we can argue about
what might or might not
happen in the future.
or you can just set all that
aside and let me hold you.
[sighs]
I really don't want to lose you.
I'm still here.
Captioning sponsored by CBS
Captioned by Media Access
Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org